Contact

carlos.reyes@cscampus.com

www.linkedin.com/in/carlosreyes-53438610 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Microsoft Operations Framework
Open Source Software
Cloud Computing

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Carlos Reyes

CTO at SipScouts and Advisor to the Executive Team at Cubicstone Beachwood, Ohio

Summary

The scope of my professional experience includes successfully managing the technology lifecycle, strategic planning and operations at large, multinational and culturally diverse institutions. My toolset includes strategic alignment, risk management, governance and compliance.

Most recently, I have been responsible for business development and marketing which has led me to acquire significant experience with inbound and outbound marketing strategies, sales and social media at a fast paced and driven startup environment.

My previous experience also includes serving as liaison to CxO and board level positions, which includes maneuvering culturally diverse and hybrid working environments.

Some of my key technical areas of expertise include emerging technologies, implementation frameworks, consulting, portfolio alignment, data integration and risk management.

Experience

Cubicstone
Advisor to the Executive Team
November 2018 - Present
Cleveland/Akron, Ohio Area

As an advisor to the executive team, my primary role is to serve as a link between external subject matter experts and the executive team while helping maintain a relevant presence across industries. An important secondary purpose is to function as institutional cultural and technical memory to improve the strategic planning process.

Sipscouts
Chief Technology Officer
October 2018 - Present

London, United Kingdom (Remote)

As CTO I have developed the technology strategy and first-hand implementation of the Sipscouts MVP and platform.

Cubicstone
Executive Director
November 2011 - November 2018 (7 years 1 month)
Cleveland/Akron, Ohio Area

As co-founder, my responsibilities have ranged from talent acquisition and retention to strategic vision and technical lead for a geographically dispersed and culturally diverse team. Additional scopes have included oversight of research and development, technological alignment with strategic goals, financial and legal oversight, as well as business development and partner/client acquisitions.

The American School Foundation, A.C. Chief Information Officer 2006 - June 2012 (6 years 6 months)

Mexico City Area, Mexico

In the role of technology lead, I was responsible for the technology life-cycle following ITIL/ MOF standards for a user base of 8, 500. Additional management domains included technology governance, strategic alignment as well as serving as liaison to board level positions. Essential areas of development included the implementation and maturing of a functional technology management framework, which translated into reliability, innovation, and cost-savings.

Deloitte - Galaz, Yamazaki, Ruiz Urquiza, S.C Data Center Operations Manager 2002 - 2004 (3 years) Mexico City Area, Mexico

In my role as Data Center Operations Manager, my central area of responsibility was the management of the technology operation and monitoring of geographically dispersed, high-availability data centers and related staff. In this role I served as Chief Architect for back-end systems where my additional responsibilities included sizing, operating and supporting critical systems to support all business units. Oversight of technical second and third level tier support was part of my job scope, as well as functioning as Latin America liaison for maintaining and building the global data center best-practices and standards body of knowledge.

The American School Foundation of Guadalajara, A.C. Director of Technology 2000 - 2001 (2 years)

Guadalajara Area, Mexico

I was directly responsible for all technology operations and the entire technology life-cycle, including both academic and administrative systems. The scope of this responsibility included infrastructure operations, monitoring, enduser technical support, vendor management and alignment with educational goals and strategy.

Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade Information Technology Manager 1999 - 2001 (3 years)

Mexico City Area, Mexico

In the role of Information Technology manager, I was responsible for the technology operations and lifecycle for all government agencies based at the embassy. This responsibility included infrastructure, communications, local and wide area networks, end-user technical support and vendor management. I was also an active participant and contributor in the generation of technology standards for the Latin American region. During this time I supervised the successful Y2K transition of the region.

Corporacion Grafica Navarrete Information Technology Manager 1997 - 1999 (3 years)

Mexico City Area, Mexico

In this role, I managed technology operations for the Mexico City office, which included telecommunications and infrastructure, end-user technical support, and in-house application maintenance and deployment. Additionally, I served as Y2K transition liaison for Mexico.

Contactos Inc./Infosel Technical Manager 1996 - 1997 (2 years) Mexico City Area, Mexico

I provided oversight of end-user technical support for the Mexico City office. I was also responsible for the technology infrastructure lifecycle, which included operating, planning and deploying new and existing technologies. I also provided technical pre-sale support for our sales force.

Productora e Importadora de Papel, S.A. Analyst 1994 - 1996 (3 years)

End-user technical support specialist and application development.

Education

Universidad de las Americas B.S., Computer Science · (1994 - 1997)